www.linkedin.com/in/theandrewdoak LINKEDIN

м 615-957-2341 **E** mrandrewdoak@gmail.com

DEVELOPER SUMMARY

Servant-leader, team player, dot-connecting thinker with a proven history of synthesizing and implementing abstract ideas and managing complex projects. Current goal is to build beautiful, useful, innovative tech products. This work is still fueled by the same "core" it always has been: creativity, superb attention to detail, dedication, open-mindedness, a growth mentality, emotional intelligence, and thoughtful, context-sensitive communication.

SKILLS SUMMARY

TECHNOLOGIES HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, p5.js, Tachyons **COMPREHENSIVE** Design systems, typography, UI/UX design, Figma, project management, command-line, Git/GitHub, networking, color management & calibration, digital/analog printmaking and camera systems, digital cinema camera operation, audio recording, studio lighting, custom framing & presentation **SOFTWARE** Photoshop, Lightroom, Capture One, Adobe Premiere, DaVinci Resolve, InDesign, Illustrator

TECHNICAL TRAINING & PROJECTS

PER SCHOLAS | 2023, October

Admitted to and graduated from competitive full-stack developer boot-camp with a social mission Acquired the equivalent of a year's hands-on training in three months, including over 900+ hours of full-time technical and professional education, plus self-study

MATCHING GAME | HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, p5.js

GitHub | Website

- Created a browser-based animated keyboard game using Dynamic HTML and p5.js, a Javascript library designed for "creative coders." Synthesized these to create a visually-rich yet challenging play experience
- · Adapted new features such as a losing criteria and different round lengths based on user-testing
- · Commended by instructor for skills, dedication, desire to learn, and for learning a new library

ART INSTITUTE SEARCH | ReactJS, CSS, REST APIs

GitHub | Website

- Created a React Single Page Application that searches the Art Institute of Chicago's API and allows the user to explore the collection, discover new works, or research known works
- Modified the data displayed from the API call based on user feedback and testing
- Designed a minimal, yet tasteful UI, which users responded to saying it feels like a real online museum

PROJECT 3 PLACEHOLDER | MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, nodeJS

GitHub | Website

- · Created a full stack MERN Application that facilitates garden-planning for the square-foot-gardener
- Modified the data displayed from the API call based on user feedback and testing
- Designed a clean UI which users responded to positively as: "feels like a real online museum"

DEPAUL UNIVERSITY | 2015-2017

Coursework in: Information Technology, Human-Computer-Interaction, Graphic Design, Designing for Physical Technology (Internet of Things), Digital Cinema Production

м 615-957-2341 **E** mrandrewdoak@gmail.com

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS OWNER, CONTRACTOR Foxtrot, Caviar | 2018-Present

- Delivered customer orders efficiently and adaptably in a high-volume, results-driven delivery environment
- Achieved top metrics in volume, (when these were shared), frequently complimented for communication style making coworkers' jobs easier

EDUCATOR & LAB ASSISTANT LATITUDE Chicago | 2016-2018

- Proposed, planned, and delivered workshops in advanced printmaking (complimented by fellow professor on the quality of teaching materials)
- Spearheaded new revenue streams & educational offerings
- Managed a fast-paced, technically complex studio while troubleshooting hardware and software, advising clients on technical and conceptual matters, accounting, and tracking inventory
- Crafted clear, thorough, detailed studio updates for management and staff (frequently singled out for this strength in meetings)

PROFESSOR OF PHOTOGRAPHY McHenry County College | 2012-2015

- Conceived, developed, and delivered a technically and creatively rigorous curriculum that was also inclusive. Solicited regular feedback adapted changes to cater to diverse learners
- Saved thousands of dollars on printing costs through efficiently managing material use without sacrificing learning.
 Reinvested surplus funds into transformative studio improvements (doubled inventory).
- Oversaw production of award-winning student magazine, Voices
- Brought LinkedIn Learning asynchronous education platform to campus

EDUCATION

CRANBROOK ACADEMY OF ART | 2009, May

Master of Fine Arts, awarded academy merit scholarship

SEWANEE: UNIVERSITY OF THE SOUTH | 2005, May

Bachelor of Arts, Photography and German

Magna cum laude, Honors in majors, awarded Wilkins merit scholarship

UNIVERSITY OF HAMBURG 2002-2003

Scholarship from the Federation of German-American Clubs for study abroad. Topics included: German, Art History, Italian, and Film Studies

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

German (fluent), Italian (proficient), Spanish (basic)

AWARDS/HONORS

2005. Fulbright Scholarship, Germany

2003. Guggenheim Museology Internship, Italy